Okay. Great.
All right.
Well, hi.
Hi, everybody.
Thanks for. Thanks for joining.
So this is the Edit
the Period wiki book workshop.
And I wanted to be a workshop,
wanted to be interactive.
And then. So maybe we'll just start.
Does anybody know?
Has anybody heard of Pure Gadget before
this?
Okay.
All right.
We have one hand.
Maybe. Okay.
Maybe on that.
Okay. Okay.
Any guesses on permits?
Everything is new. Sorry.
Everything is new. Okay. Okay.
So peer is.
Are you all familiar with pedagogy
or pedagogy?
Some.
Some people say it.
And then the.
So pedagogy, like,
you know, as you know, the teachers
in front of the room
giving information to other people
and like somebody who has information,
giving it to people who don't conceivably.
And then not always the case,
but a high level and then pure
is, you know, a peer is aspired by peer
learning and peer production.
And so it's a it's a learning.
It's a theory of
how how people learn together.
Like as without without a hierarchy.
And then so
and this
has been an art we've done on our research
that hasn't been studied
as much as pedagogy and pedagogy.
There's,
you know, at least like 200 years or
more of literature about there, about it.
And people are very familiar with.
Yeah, how that can work
and how different ideas of how it works.
Well.
But then peer is not as, yeah,
not as formally defined, but
some examples of pure.
You know, if you're making
if a group of people come together
to form a form a rock band or form a,
you know, form a hip hop group
or some other type of music engagement,
like they aren't
necessarily maybe one person knows
a little more about it than another,
or some people have more experience,
but you're kind of like coming together
to make something or news together,
or like in the 70s.
And people were,
you know, before there were a
lot of like computer science
classes or programing classes, people who,
you know, wrote operating systems
and made a lot of the made computers,
they weren't necessarily
they didn't like, go to school.
They went to school to learn some things,
but they were really,
you know, making
it up together as they were
going along.
So that's we're trying to document.
You know, with peer document
techniques that work well and
better understanding of the ideas
that I'll be able to come together
and less and nonhierarchical settings
to get things done.
And then another example,
or of course, you know, an old school,
I mean, people who like, you know,
the first humans who figured out how to
make fire and control it, like they didn't
go to like, Cambridge University,
you know, a couple thousand years ago
today.
Think, you know, they made fire.
And then probably some people got burnt
and some people maybe didn't, you know,
but those who stayed alive,
they passed on the knowledge
and, you know, controlled it.
And then so so that's peer
and then okay, so that's,
that's what we're talking about today.
And the pure guy I've been involved
with it for a number of years now.
And then there's a there's a peer review
handbook you can get download for free
online a PDF version, or you can get it
from Amazon or other other places.
And the only game is on source on bookshop
and and in some bookstores
in Chicago, on the shelves,
independent bookstores and then
so that's peer.
And then with the version of the handbook
we're going to talk about
today is on wiki books.
Have any of you all heard of wiki books?
Okay.
And then so it is a
it's a sister project of Wikipedia, which,
you know, everybody's
looking at this point.
Do we have any, any
or any of you Wikipedia editors.
Okay.
Now today.
Great, great.
Okay. That's that's a start.
All right. Hi, Dina.
Thanks for.
Thanks for joining.
And hello, Bay.
So so yeah, Wikipedia is obviously.
Yeah, perfect is
one of the most successful, you know,
a top ten website in the world, I think
only one that's run by a nonprofit.
And then it has some sister projects
that are that are, you know,
they're not as bad as visited,
but also have a lot of volunteers
there who are making them resources.
And so one specifically
we're talking about today is Wicked Books.
And so, yeah, Dina added the,
the link and then.
Oh, man.
Okay. Yeah for sure. Join the deep. Yes.
Let's join that as well
I need to join that.
Thank you.
And then okay okay okay.
Great.
And then so I don't even know about that.
And so. Yeah.
So book
specifically I'm going to share my screen.
We're going to go to
I'll give the URL first.
So we're going to a specific wiki book
this one.
So we got the Wikipedia doesn't have ads
but they do have they do have banners.
And so we got the Mickey books.
They got the the upcoming Wikimedia.
Another three.
Another cool online.
That's hybrid conference. But that's cool.
So this is the peer
handbook wiki book edition.
And this is what we're going to be
going through today and talking about.
And so yeah, so as I mentioned,
you know, it's kind of gives a little
introduction to the concept.
And then
it has currently has 31
different chapters or sections.
And and then here in the references
we talk about the some of the other
versions of the handbook.
And then this is
and then this is kind of
the center of peer is a peer guide. Org.
And here you can find
like the mentioned like the
the third edition of the handbook.
It came out in 2016.
This is here. And you can 278 pages.
You can go through.
But that's like, you know, a lot of pages
and we haven't we haven't seen as much.
There are people yeah, people
who've read this and cited it and used it,
which has been great. But it's also it's
kind of, you know, it's a lot.
278 pages intimidating to start with,
something new.
Like I said,
you can also get a print edition.
But so the
and then this is also it is available
and you can yeah you can go to
our GitHub and you can try to
on the
GitHub you can make your own version.
But but for
but that's you know choir amount know how
and it doesn't doesn't
and it doesn't have like the community
aspect that Wikipedia does, which is
you know, I mean got millions of editors
around the world
making changes in real time and, and yeah,
within electronic literature,
I mean, it's obviously I
it wasn't the first like
electronic literature encyclopedia,
but certainly the most successful.
And you know better than I mean,
I think it's best to
humans have ever come together to make
and then and yeah,
there's like less errors than Britannica
and then but okay.
So so the idea is like with that community
people can come in and edit.
And then so some people know here already,
like on any page
Wikipedia
or Ricky books, there's this view history.
And so you can see.
So that's I made some changes
you know other people.
And then I don't know this Dirk
I don't know Dirk.
But Dirk came in and checked
and like it reviewed a lot of things.
And then Dirk
even just also made a, a separate,
a new PDF version
that we didn't have before
just for the a PDF of the, the wiki book.
And then so this is a little different.
But then so this is static here.
But we did it last
within the last few weeks.
And then so this has everything here.
So this is also a nice thing.
If you use the media wiki software
it can export to a PDF very cleanly.
And so so somebody. Yeah.
So we never met Dirk.
He came in and made that you know
did that and improved the resource.
So that's an example of what
we're trying to grow with
with the community
and get more people involved okay.
Done a lot of talking pause
any any questions
or comments
or anything if I want to share.
Actually, yeah.
Thank you for this.
I did not know about wiki books.
So yeah, we're expanding.
How does the wiki books actually work
and how is it linked into Wikipedia?
For example, if there's an article
about Paraguay and what it does with that,
and Wikipedia with that link back to this
or what's the connections?
Okay, so so the connections like
so they're both part of.
Like that's not it.
Like yeah.
So part of the Wikimedia Foundation
and like the Wikimedia movements
I suppose.
But so they're both projects here.
And then so obviously
the is yeah, biggest one.
But then Wiki Books is over here.
I kind of I've also done thinking
about converse but so this is their both.
And then MediaWiki itself
is the software that's used for Wikipedia.
And so that's
so they're both part of the same like
nonprofit umbrella
to answer that and sister projects.
And then in terms of
like connecting back and forth.
So there is
you know, with as you
I'm sure you know, Adina
and others may have discovered,
you know, the, the,
the language for editing
Wikipedia pages
and then is this wiki text.
And there's if you go down to this level,
you can see it.
And they also have more of a,
a GUI source.
There's also a GUI option that is nice.
And then here you can go in
and make changes like directly.
I'm not going to do that right now.
But then so that
but just going back to the.
We've this
discard my edits so you can
so you can do these.
It's called inter wiki linking.
And so like this particular link
like it's a slightly different color
than this is a link inside of wiki books.
And so this is the project page or like
linking to like you know the foreword.
It's a certain it's a certain color
blue and a lighter shade of blue is this
links
to the Wikipedia page for UC Berkeley.
So and then on some.
I'm not going to I'm not sure.
Like one example would be like
like for
let's just say I don't know what that is.
What that World Cup. Wow.
England's playing. That was unintentional.
But yeah thank you.
And thank you all for joining here.
Well the World Cup is on the
okay.
But so as an example
like the way that some of the
so this is the you know declaration or
well I guess lots of declaration.
That's good. It should be
it shouldn't just go to the USA.
Should go to all of them.
Okay. That's good.
And then so.
All right.
Well here just trying to show a.
Show.
Another example of.
Okay so this is Declaration
of Independence.
You can read about that.
It's strengths weaknesses.
Edit this page.
And then yeah just to show for others
who may not know like Dana like
this is and I have an account right now
I'm logged in.
But you need to have a it's easier
if you have an account.
You don't have to have one.
But then like here Dina.
So like this is
this source is another project.
And so here if you want to actually
just read the full text,
you can go here
and actually has a bunch of different.
But now you're in a different I'm
not sure if you can see my browser,
but you're no longer.
So this is like so that's kind
of how the sister projects connects.
There's like inter wiki linking
and then across projects.
If you do have a Wikipedia account
you can then edit wiki books.
Yeah. Yeah. Yes.
And then we'll test that.
We will test that today. And then
and you should also like depending
depending on where you are in the world.
Like you should be able to edit
without logging in.
But I think because of
and it used to be used to build,
everybody used to be able
edit without logging in.
But now I think they've done
there's more like if you're signing up
for the first time on a mobile phone,
I've heard that sometimes,
like mobile phones get blocked
or some some universities
or yeah, I guess university,
but a lot of spam.
But you should be able to,
especially if you're like at home
that's come in and create an account
and then
come in here and make some edits.
And then so I think this would be there.
Yeah. Well okay.
That was a good question, Dina. All right.
That was a good question.
Any other questions about peer
or wiki books or Wikimedia?
Yes, please.
As I understood, we keep Wikipedia.
We can be editors.
And it is a kind of peer reviewed.
We do this, the other one
review each other.
It seems like that.
And this paragraph, how can you,
revise or
control or.
Yeah, control is a bad word, but yeah.
How can you manage and administrator
the collaboration.
So yeah.
Great question. So so yes. Yeah.
Wikipedia like has the,
you know, one person makes a change
and then some people,
some people do a review it sometimes
and revert it if it's, you know, if,
if they said something
that was inaccurate or different things.
And then so with this, with this version
of the handbook, it's similar.
We don't like it's
you can see the the history.
Everybody who's done changes here.
And I
you know I've been doing more recently.
But this goes back and then so
and then like Dirk
so this like Dirk came in on June 13th
and did this reviewed version.
So I'd been making changes
earlier this year and then they
hadn't been reviewed.
And then so Dirk
did that and cleared that.
And then now
there's been an additional change.
But so you can see all the different
people who have gone in and manage this.
And then so that's the beginning answer.
So that so that tracks everything.
And so something is like
erroneous or somebody,
you know, says something that's like,
you know,
about a different topic or something
that's not nice or something, you know,
we can go in and control it there.
And then there still is like the admin
level of there are administrators in wiki
books that have, you know, privileges
and rights that not everybody else has.
So that's
but that's kind of independent of here.
So with this was less
kind of
the software itself, the software itself
and the structure of the like.
Same as Wikipedia.
The project itself
is kind of the managing of it,
but it's a little it's also like a lot
more like freeform and wild than like,
whereas like with the with the first three
editions of the handbook like that, we.
Are you still seeing my screen,
you seeing the different screen now.
Are you still okay.
So like here like
this is like we control the
you know, we control the domain
like those of us in the Peer Gods project.
Like the editors control the domain.
And this is a static HTML page.
So this is so we have,
you know, complete oversight here.
But then this like and we had some good
you know, we've had great contributors.
And like from 2012, 2014, 2016,
we put out new additions every two years.
But then people, you know, things happen.
People get bit like any like
like some open source software projects.
People lives change and things.
And then so we haven't,
we haven't put out something new.
And so we become kind of a bottleneck
for like
creating new versions and that we don't,
you know, we don't want that.
And especially with peer guys,
you shouldn't be like hierarchical.
It should be like
just more distributed. So,
so the
there's less control or less oversight
here.
Gisella.
But that's like and I think that's a
that's good.
That's like a strength of this,
of being here is that we can have
more people can come in that is good.
And it does note that you have to approve
the changes, unlike Wikipedia
where the changes are made
and then you find out about it.
But for example, I just
I confess I made a change really fast
and the history
and then you would basically review
that your authors would review that
and see if it was right or not.
So these are moderated,
which is but I think
it's. Cool, but I think it's
where did you make the change?
I think it's still awaiting review.
Yeah. Here.
What was what was the change?
The change was I changed.
Experiences within the pedagogy
project had been that I just changed it
to the pedagogy project has found that,
you know,
just an editorial.
Yeah, I see, I see, I see and then.
But it didn't.
Whoops.
Not to hijack your presentation.
No no no no no, this is what we
this is what we want.
Yeah.
Interesting. But
I thought it would.
So then I.
But it's kind of good that somebody else
needs to approve it is what I'm thinking.
Yeah,
but then that's like a new bottleneck.
Oh, that's true.
That's what we were trying to.
Yeah.
So the current.
Okay.
Sorry we're on all these different.
All right.
I'm just gonna refresh tab.
You can see all my search history.
They're all friends here. Right. The.
And then.
Maybe it's a pending change
because you haven't.
Like, you think you might have to like,
maybe you're not interesting because.
Yeah. Like your what?
Your user page on Wicked Books
hasn't been created yet.
But let me see.
But see.
Well, this is good.
This is why we're we're learning.
Okay.
Because if I and I'm not, I'm not seeing.
Are you seeing a place where I can
now approve this?
I'm not
right.
And that's.
All right.
Well, so that's okay.
So I guess they're going to be.
But then.
Okay, now let's just go to the.
So I.
What's interesting is that
if you are an editor on Wikipedia,
which is really important, you
that information doesn't necessarily
come back over to wiki books.
So you need to well,
even though you can be logged
in, you need to put a specific user
page specifically for wiki books.
You do. Yes. You do need. That's correct.
Yeah. Yeah that's great.
Great point. Yeah.
So you need to have a separate user page.
And I'm just going
to do a quick test here. See
I am we
do have the
Wikipedia electronic literature project.
I'll put that in the chat.
But one of the things that I've been doing
is saying, hey,
if you work for six months
and do 500 edits,
you get access to the Wikipedia library,
which in the United States
is really critical
now, especially for independent
people who don't have a library.
It's you get like literally thousands
of dollars worth of subscriptions
with just that is the came
if my if I added on wiki books
does that count.
Do you know I do not know.
That's a great question. Yes.
And then yeah like,
you know, love these plugs for Wikipedia.
Are you still okay?
All right.
And then here let me just see
like okay.
One okay.
There's one pending change.
And then this has, this has the.
Yeah this has the updated language.
Right. The period has.
That's what you did has found.
Okay. Yeah.
That's all I did.
But some people say
you're not supposed to end the sentence
with the with it, you know.
So take the ball around with it
on their own, okay?
Okay.
And then this should.
So now I wonder
two pending changes. Okay. Wow.
So there's more.
So now.
So this has to be reviewed.
Okay.
Well so that's a
that's unfortunate actually.
You know you reviews it
like if you're the author
of the handbook I'm still not quite
getting how wicked Books works.
I'm sorry.
No, no. It's okay.
Yeah.
So like Dirk, Dirk reviewed it like here.
Like he did like this.
Like checked.
And then I don't.
So these are
the versions that have been checked over.
So yeah. Going back to.
Last few years.
And so it might be.
Yeah I don't know.
Okay.
Well that we'll have to
come back to that one
or unless somebody else
figure out during the call.
But then okay, let's
forgetting deep into this is good.
This is good.
We're getting deep into.
MediaWiki software here okay.
So it's appending changes
and then does that.
Is everybody
on your people
who aren't like have an account.
Do you see the same thing up the top here.
If you go to the
I'll put it in the chat again.
It should still be in the chat but.
Are other people
also seeing this like kind of review all
review hold.
Okay okay.
Thank you. Thank you Lyle.
All right
well so we'll come back to that one.
Any other.
Any other questions
about appear guides
or wiki books or Wikimedia.
And then let's has anybody
anybody who is anybody
tried to make an account on the call.
And already have one.
Okay, great.
And then
okay, so that so we saw
how that works with the
edits here.
And then let's just try let's
see if that also happens on.
Let's just.
I guess
Dina goes up to this latest draft tab
which they don't have on Wikipedia.
This kind of like so it's like it's.
Okay.
So the latest draft has
the changes, but then the
it feels like a very
recent change I don't okay.
You know it's
like when you're doing the demo right.
You know,
that's when you get all the fun stuff.
Yeah. Okay.
So let's now let's try,
let's go to the just go to the overview.
Let's see what happens here okay.
So overview.
And this is a little.
This is longer.
And then this one was written more for.
For wiki books.
So it has some of the formatting
and things you would expect in
more of like looks
almost more like Wikipedia page.
And then.
And also yeah we can take a nice
also you can take advantage of like images
that are in
in Wikimedia Commons and.
And then yeah,
the reference is of course great.
And then this goes back to
the handbook and then okay.
And then like.
I get involved.
So on this one
this one hasn't really been changed
I think since very few updates.
2020 Shakespeare fan.
Thank you.
But you know, not a lot of changes
since 2013 and 2013.
The person who put it in, they didn't
they weren't even logged in.
They just had like they just used their
their IP address, which is.
Yeah, that's a nice it seems like a
kind of a, you know, a dangerous feature.
But as you know, as we've seen
now over decades of Wikipedia, it ends up
leading to more.
To better quality resources.
And then so let's try editing this one.
Okay.
And then so this was kind of
put this and we don't really have
we don't have any illustrations
on this page currently.
And then.
But okay on the
e-books version on this okay.
Books version of the handbook,
you can get involved
by making edits yourself.
Look at it above and then.
Sure, you're going to get into this, but
what if I don't know
anything about period,
and I start making edits that say, hey,
this must be pedagogy,
and there's obviously mistake or,
you know, something that would be wrong,
how to fix that?
Or that you have to have like references
because like in Wikipedia,
you have to have a reference that says,
hey, this is the fact, okay?
But you don't need to have that here.
You do not need references here.
No, it's more like the book itself
is the the reference material.
And then so
yeah.
And then so like a feature and similar to.
Similar to
Wikipedia, they also have,
you know like featured books.
So it looks like there's a book on
it's currently featured.
And then this one's
a little more organized.
Than the handbook.
And then so but like this is like this
could you know,
you can you can have references of course,
but it's not a requirement.
Like conceivably a wiki book
could be like a reference for a Wikipedia.
Now look at the article itself.
Without getting to get too far into the
the but like and then.
And then here's like you know,
if you wanted to learn about Arabic.
And so this is a textbook
for learning Arabic and then.
So it.
Yeah.
And so like this itself is the
these are the lessons and then yeah,
this doesn't have any references
because it's like this is
the learning resource itself.
And then.
So that,
so if somebody were to
so that would be like
to, to your back to your question
somebody where to put
something about pedagogy
that was not there that would be,
you know, it'd be up to the review
and then it could go.
And of course like also
it could go to The.
Somebody to review it
and check it and then as well, you know,
that's something that could be discussed
in the here,
like somebody could say with Wikipedia,
like if you have a problem with the
or you have a question about the page,
you can post it on the talk page.
So that is also an option
as well on on wiki books.
And then.
Yeah.
Does that kind of
kind of answer your question
okay.
All right.
It that way.
Because that way you can look
at the latest draft, but you can also look
at the draft that somebody presumably
an author has checked.
So that's really good.
Yeah.
And then like and then the. Yes.
And then also like
the PDF like this needs to be done.
This is, this was done at a point in time.
So this one like doesn't have are you
seeing like a red line on my screen.
Okay.
That was that was on intentional of
I zoom skills
here. The.
Chat.
The fictional books.
That's a good question Gizelle.
Let me see.
I think that
I think wiki,
I think fiction might be outside
the scope of wiki books.
But we could do a work.
For example, we could do a book
about electronic literature here.
Yes, for sure.
All of the electronic literature stuff.
That would be amazing.
Yes, that is a great. Yeah.
And that something that also could be like
as in that.
And we could look for volunteers in the,
the wiki project that you cited.
And then.
Okay. Yeah.
So this is for.
Non. Yeah.
Instructional nonfiction books.
And then if you
so that and then I mean
and I'll work around for that.
Gisella.
If you did if you did really want to
this was like if you, you know a big fan
you want to put your stuff here.
You can always something you can do is
you can put you can add pages to your own,
like user profile for stuff
that maybe you don't feel is like.
And then as an example, like I put,
this is my my main hormone
look media is I'm looking
and then so like these were
like I added this
like sub page, my user profile.
You could put like your fiction in there.
But but yeah.
So I think it's not,
it's not designed for,
for fiction
it appears.
Let's just try.
Yeah.
It's like kind of.
About fiction and.
And. Yeah.
So follows the policies of.
Okay great great questions.
Any other.
Questions for right now
ba any questions or comments.
Okay.
So and then I think.
And also just take a step back
I think like you know I don't want
don't want peer guys.
You to seem like it's
something that is like yeah it wasn't
I mean like I may have worked on it
research,
but it was, you know, some of the people
and also it shouldn't be that
we don't want this to be
like an intimidating thing or like so,
so all, I mean, all of you,
I'm sure, have experiences with like peer
learning
or peer production in your own lives
and you know, and then
any, any examples come to mind
that you all like,
want to share of your own,
your own experiences?
Actually, yeah.
I'm wondering how this can work.
This is wonderful for peer.
I have a rare disease and.
Basically we've been accused
of Munchausen and
hypochondria because obviously something
can't be that complex.
Actually it can.
And I do have a work MHC.
I'll put it in the chat
where I have gone through 70
peer reviewed articles
about my my rare disease.
It would be way cool to put that up here.
And I see that in the chat.
Lyle says that you can do it for knitting.
That's.
Yeah,
it's a great example up here for sure.
Yeah, yeah.
Pretty much.
Thank you very much for letting me.
Go through this, but
I put in the URL for my talk.
We have 70 peer reviewed reports.
I would love to have something like this
be on that.
Could this be a Wikipedia
page?
I mean, I think,
I mean, in my opinion,
I think like, oh, we keep book.
I mean, I think it could definitely be
a wiki book, but I think this could also
if it's not, is there not is there
currently a Wikipedia article about this?
There is currently a Wikipedia article,
and we have been putting these notes in.
The problem, quite frankly,
is that it's a tenuous connection.
M80 does not produce HSP.
We found that out.
HSP does a hell of a lot for your body
if you do not have.
So the tenuous connection
logic is if you don't have it,
that cute little protein
sugar, you may have problems.
Also sort of things about like
none of us are being taken seriously,
all of our tests are normal
and we have problems, right?
So this says, hey, here's
what you talk to doctors about.
Or this is, hey, here are all of the peer
reviewed stuff.
Yeah. Wow.
Yeah.
This is I mean, yeah, kudos to you for
wow, all this this is very, very thorough.
So. Yeah.
So, so so, yeah,
I think this would absolutely fit as,
like, a new wiki book and then, Yeah.
And you already have an account.
Yeah, you can start a new one.
And then I could,
I could link the articles
that are in Wikipedia about MHC to this.
Right, right. Yes.
And then that would be that,
that inter wiki linking would just be like
you'd be like a w colon and then the name
rather than just the article name.
Like so like
not sure I understand.
So typically like with a.
If you're linking.
Like WP or production or W.
Yeah. Yeah.
And then this goes to Wikipedia.
Whereas like you know if you, if you were,
if you were inside Wikipedia
you wouldn't need the W.
You could just have the,
you know that article.
So that's how you do the wiki links.
And then we can
like quick snap, airy.
And then whereas like.
Yeah.
And these are like you don't need that,
you don't need the colon here
because these are inside of looking books.
These are direct links to the other
to the pages.
That makes sense.
And this
but I also want to make sure
that we get back to your topic.
Did you want to know? Yeah.
No, this is we are we are.
You know, I don't really go back.
Yeah. No, this is we we are.
This is like,
this is supposed to be introduction
to peer and to wiki books and and so
and you and you've already
you accomplished one of the goals
of like making an edit.
And so I was hoping
that people would make it. Yeah.
So and I think your the
the study and what,
what is MHC stands for again
multiple hereditary access tosses.
That was actually
the problem is we have bone tumors.
And so everybody says
oh you have bone tumors.
You have no other problems.
There's a reason why we have bone tumors.
And that causes everything else.
Okay okay.
Got it, got it. Okay.
So I think that what you've come like
the knowledge you've come together in that
like that Google doc I think is like
that's an example here in action.
And so that's like yeah.
And like that's like such peers
coming together to learn.
You were learning about it together
from each other and like yeah.
And then you couldn't like
you went to doctors, you went to like the,
you used the hierarchy and got kind of
rejected, you know, and like
and then so then you came together
and you learned more about it on your own.
Turns out there was research out there
already.
You just had to like, look for it.
And then you peer produced
this new resource.
So that is yeah,
that's an example of here in action.
Oh, it totally is.
And if I may really quickly
before the internet,
they just thought it was a bone disease.
But once the internet got together
and everybody said, hey,
we all have the weird ND stuff,
we are not.
We're neurodiverse in a weird way.
Oh, that's part of the heparin sulfate.
And that's actually helping
to focus autism research.
So it really is a peer
because of the internet.
And we were before the internet, my mother
and I thought we were the only ones
in the world with this disease.
There was still only 300 of us in the US.
It's really stupid rare.
I've never been to a medical person
who's ever heard of it.
And so
we got together.
We're looking at this rare disease,
and it has been a period
of research into what we have.
Thank you. Okay.
Now I know the word.
Yeah. Exactly. And then. Yeah.
And then you could even
or you could even say it's periodical the
and then the and. Yeah.
And then the internet is a big.
Yeah a big because like, you know,
the people who we've been working,
I've been working with this on
some are in the US,
but like most, you know, a lot of people
are in different parts of the world.
And then so we like peer
has been happening
since, you know, and there's lots of
and we came up with a new name pure
because like, there wasn't a name before,
but not trying to create a new name for
the sake of it for the sake of a new name.
But like it's been, people been learning
from each other, obviously,
you know,
as long as humans have been learning
and then so but with the internet,
it's like way
like you could people could collaborate
on a book before the internet.
You could like, you know, mail
a copy to somebody else or something,
and they can do their edits
and they can mail it back.
And that was happening.
That was happening.
People were doing that
in the 19th century, 19th century.
People were like, you know,
there were scholars working in UK
and US or Asia,
you know, other places that that happened.
But it's just slow, you know,
and it's not like it's not.
And then so this speeds it up
and then also like it
speeds it up and introduces possibilities
that like were just, you know,
you have to be very established
to be able to like to get to that point
where you even know somebody over there.
And so, yeah,
the internet is a big part of it.
And then knitters nice.
The welcome,
welcome hijackers and Highlanders.
Definitely welcome to this this session.
The and so yeah.
And then
I think
and so
like so I think this is like a use case.
And then I would say like we can do
we can edit this.
And so I would say
because I wanted to put something
from this, this session in here as well.
And then so I would say.
We all need to do the
for the sake of the video.
We need to do the and watch.
I'm going to do at the level of the.
Okay.
So use case we can have.
Online 2026 workshop.
Is there a
is there already like an L page on the
on Wikipedia.
Do you know.
Yes there is.
And if you just do wiki
I put it in the chat and let me.
I think if you do w WP lit it should work.
I don't know because there's
going to be colons in that.
Let me
go back and get the actual URL.
Look at that.
Oh there it is.
Oh, you did it.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
This.
Here and
the media
and like it looks is.
And let's see how it does
on this side, how it does the,
I can handle the of
if I may appear at this conference
is in the discord.
Now we have a list of missing people
because we took
pictures of folks
to go into Wikipedia Wikimedia.
At the ILO conference last year, and
I lost the lists.
Face blind.
So now you're doing a period
of identifying these people.
Great, great.
Yeah.
Another great use case.
This works.
And then.
And do you want to want me to reference
the MH?
As another use case?
Okay.
And we discovered
in the definitely do that.
Some I do have a work about the MHC.
So I am out there in public.
That is fine. Okay.
I'm actually going to put my
the net first is the work about my mother
and my and this lovely disease.
Yeah that's my mother
and that's her bone tumor.
And then are you
and if you.
Yeah if you scroll down you'll see it.
But yeah. On the page.
Yeah.
This is actually a twine work.
And you can see the.
Wow. This is very thorough, Dina.
Oh yeah.
We have 800 pictures of her body.
Yeah.
This is.
Yeah. So you've been you're doing it.
You been doing it?
Yeah.
Okay.
But I promise, after this workshop,
I will get together
with our group and we will make a wiki
wiki book about this.
And then when we do,
we'll link back to your period.
Hey, thanks.
Awesome, awesome. Thank.
Awesome. Okay.
Okay.
Cool. All right.
And then so we'll see
I guess this might be.
And this is probably
also a cultural thing.
Always always put a note
about what you changed
so that when somebody goes back
through the view history.
They know what it is.
Absolutely okay.
And it looks like this one was published.
So maybe it's like
I'm learning about wiki books here too.
But this one now
looks like this is actually I'm
gonna put this link in the chat.
Let me know if you see that live.
Okay,
so maybe it's just the home page has,
but yeah, but so this is how
I thought it was going to work.
So it should just be.
So anybody on that link
if you go in right now.
Either anonymously or with an account,
you should be able to like.
And you want to add
this is our section here.
So if you want to edit this
or talk about your experience,
you can do that right here.
And then it looks like and it looks like
it did handle the it handle the.
So. And we're linking up to the
our electronic literature project.
And okay great.
Any other questions or comments.
And then
okay.
And then also just this like this
like 1.0 like
so we had like
previously like we were kind of taking a
like a PDF like electronic literature PDF
or like print book approach to this.
You know, it's like first edition,
second edition and like that.
Just that's why we had 1.0
and we also had Periodic Handbook 2.0,
but that didn't really for wiki
books like the version
number changes every single time
somebody makes an edit.
So there's no.
So that was like it's not appropriate
for this type of electronic literature.
It's not it's unnecessary
to have the version numbers in the title.
So now there's just the handbook. And then
and so it's all just a single thing.
And this is supposed to stand on
and so on.
And. Yeah.
Anything else?
Any other
examples of a period in action
people want to share from their own,
their own lives or experiences?
To review, to, to validate this,
because this page
may need to be reviewed for quality.
We should, yes, create
an account in Wicked books
or we can do this
from our Wikipedia account.
So if you're logged in to
if you're logged in to Wikipedia,
it should be it's the same login page
and the same
it's not same long page,
it's the same account name and password.
And then like when Dina did it like you
on each project,
you need to create your own
user, a new user page.
And so that's kind of a so
but after you do that, Gisella and
or even even before you do that,
just like, yeah, if you go to wiki books,
you should be able to start making edits
and then
and this
but yeah, this reviewed for quality.
This is like like I mean, I've been
I mean I've been in wiki books
for a long time and like this,
I just made a change
and it still needs to be reviewed.
So I think like
yeah this like review process.
So it looks like reviewers.
Yeah.
It's like a certain regular you can become
a review after a certain point.
But I guess I haven't gone to that point.
Or maybe it's because I'm not allowed
to review this particular book
because I've done so many changes.
Okay.
All right.
And then.
Yes. Thank you.
No, no, moderating is good, I think.
Yeah,
I think we accomplished more than I was.
I was hoping to hear today.
Wow. All right.
We already started the wiki book.
That is awesome. Okay, you know what?
Oh, I guess I can. I'm
going to accept this revision.
Here we go.
Okay, so that goes to the.
Yeah.
Very clean. Goes to the Wikipedia.
Look at that. Okay there we go.
And so hopefully this should be I guess.
Yeah. So I was able to review
I was able to review that one
because I haven't touched it.
So maybe that's like if you touch it then.
So but.
Okay.
Well this was
this was great.
Thank you all so much
for your participation and engagement.
And thank you, Emily
and the team at Florida.
And I'm trying to go to your organization
for putting on this incredible event.
At first time.
I just found out about this.
Yeah, earlier this year.
And yeah, really excited to be to be here.
And then I'll just put my email
in the chat and wants to stay in touch.
And or I can see you on I'll see you there
session
here in this cord
or or Mickey books Grand.
Thank you so much.
And welcome to the ELO.
We do like this all the time.
Awesome. Like for you to.